olympicholidays.com 2019-09-25

# Privacy Policy | Olympic Holidays

This Privacy Policy applies in all your dealings with us even if any of the arrangements you book with us are supplied by a third party (such as an accommodation supplier or airline), as this Privacy Policy forms part of your [Booking](http://www.easyjet.com/en/terms-and-conditions) Conditions and your contract with us .

Olympic Holidays is committed to protecting your privacy and, as well as your personal safety, the safety and security of the information you provide us with. We take our responsibilities regarding the security of customer information very seriously. This privacy policy explains what personal data we collect about you, how and why we use it, who we disclose it to, and how we protect your privacy.

  1. **Who is responsible for your data**

Our Privacy Policy applies to the personal data that Olympic Holidays collects and uses.

References in this Privacy Policy to “Olympic Holidays”, “we”, “us” or “our” mean Travelworld Vacations Limited (a company registered in Guernsey with registration no. 29828 and registered office at Avenue House, St Julian's Avenue, St Peter Port, Guernsey GA1 1WA). We control the ways your personal data are collected and the purposes for which your personal data are used by Olympic Holidays and are the “data controller” for the purposes of the UK Data Protection Act 1998 ("UKDPA"), and other applicable European data protection legislation including the General Data Protection Regulations (EU) 2016/679 ("GDPR").   The department responsible for your personal data and its processing by Olympic Holidays is the Operations department, who can be contacted by email at privacypolicy@olympicholidays.com or by post to 1 Torrington Park, London, N12 9TB.

  2. **Personal data we collect about you**

When using the term “personal data” in our Privacy Policy, we mean information that relates to you and allows us to identify you, either directly or in combination with other information that we may hold. Your personal data may include for example your name, your contact details, information relating to your travel itinerary (e.g. your booking reference number) or information on how you use our website or you interact with us by telephone, email or other means of communication.

We collect some personal data from you on various occasions, for example when you book a holiday with us, use our website, use our services or contact us. We may also receive your personal data from our suppliers who provide services to you on our behalf (for example when you provide feedback on our services), our partners when you purchase their travel related products or third parties who act on your behalf, for example travel agents or other parties who book a holiday for you. If you book a holiday or other arrangement with us on behalf of someone else, you must have their consent to use their personal information.

For more information on the persons or organisations who may share your personal data with us, please see section 7 below.

**Categories of data we collect**

We may collect and process the following categories of information about you:

Your name and surname and your contact details  
(email address, telephone number and postal address)

| 

When you ask for a quote from us

When you book a flight, inclusive holiday or accommodation arrangement.  
When you take part in our promotional activity or competitions, or  
When you choose an offer we make available on our website

When you apply for a job whether in the UK or overseas.  
  
---|---  
  
Information about your bookings and your travel itinerary, if you require special assistance or if you have specific dietary requirements. This  information may include any changes to your bookings and travel products that relate to your booking (for example if you purchase allocated seats or additional luggage or if you purchase travel insurance, rent a car or book any other pre-bookable service with, or subsequent to, your  holiday, flight or accommodation booking).

| 

When you book, amend or manage your holiday, flight or accommodation  
  
Information about your health, if you have a medical condition that may affect your flight or accommodation choice or requirements or any insurance arrangements booked through us  (please see section “Sensitive personal data”   below for more information).

| 

When you provide us with this information when booking or subsequently  
  
Information about other passengers in your booking, and the ages of any children travelling with you.

| 

When you make a booking, which includes, and is made on behalf of, other passengers  
  
Information about your transaction, including   your payment card details

| 

When you book a holiday or other arrangement or purchase any products or services we offer.  
  
Advance Passenger Information. This information includes your full name, your nationality, your   date of birth, your gender (where required) - the number and type of your travel document (e.g. passport or ID), its expiry date and country of   issue

| 

When you provide this information to meet government/airline requirements.  
  
Information about your purchases of our partners’ travel related products and services 

| 

When you purchase such products or services  
  
The communications you exchange with us (for example, your emails, letters, or calls,)

| 

When you contact us or you are contacted by us.  
  
Your posts and messages on social media   directed to Olympic Holidays 

| 

When you interact with us on social media   
  
Your feedback

| 

When you reply to our requests for feedback or participate in our customer surveys  
  
Your preferred departure locations

| 

When you choose to provide this information while requesting a quote or making a booking.  
  
Information about how you use our website, such as your searches for flights

| 

When you navigate on our website  
  
**Sensitive or special categories of personal data  **

In the course of providing services to you, we may collect information that could reveal your racial or ethnic origin, physical or mental health, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or alleged commission or conviction of criminal offences. Such information is considered “sensitive personal data” under UKDPA and other data protection laws and as a special category of personal data under GDPR. We only collect and process this information where you have given your explicit consent, it is necessary, or you have deliberately made it public. 

For example, we may collect this information in the following circumstances:

For your safety, when you have a specific medical condition which might affect your ability to take a flight, or the accessibility of accommodation, or the availability or cost of travel insurance, you will need to inform us of that and –where required – provide us with medical evidence.

If you request special assistance to transit an airport, or on board an aircraft, this could reveal information about your health (for example if you ask for a wheelchair). If you inform us about specific dietary requirements you may have, this could potentially indicate that you have specific religious or philosophical beliefs. Also, when you provide us with your travel document details, your nationality may imply your racial or ethnic origin.

By providing any sensitive or special categories of personal data you are explicitly agreeing that we may collect and process it as necessary in order to provide the services you have requested or booked and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

If you do not consent to us processing any sensitive or special categories of personal data (and you will need to make this clear to us when asked for such data), this may mean we are unable to provide all or parts of the services you have booked or requested from us. Please be aware that in such circumstances you will not be entitled to cancel any booked service (although we may be obliged to cancel or refuse to provide any such service) or obtain a refund of any price you have paid.  

  3. **How and why we use your personal data**

  * We process and use your personal data for the following purposes, which provide the legal grounds under GDPR on the basis of which we may retain and process your personal data, namely: (a) the performance of our contract with you, whether you are a customer who has booked travel or other arrangements with us, or you have applied for a job or are already employed; or (b) we have a legal obligation to retain and process your personal data, for instance to comply with our statutory obligations to have our accounts audited and to retain certain records for a fixed period of time or to make returns to H M Revenus and Customs if you are an employee; (c) we have a legitimate interest in retaining and processing your personal data, that is we have a legitimate business or commercial interest in doing so.   
  * **To manage your travel bookings and provide our and others' services to you**

When you are holidaying or flying with us or using accommodation booked from us, we use your information to perform our services in relation to your holiday, flight, or accommodation for example to issue your ATOL certificate and itinerary, check you in for your flight (if we do this online for you), ensure that a transfer or hire car is available to you on arrival at your destination and that you have access to the accommodation you have booked. We also use it to change your booking if you request such changes or they become necessary for other reasons. 

  * **To communicate with you and manage our relationship with you**

Occasionally we may need to contact you by email and/or post for administrative or operational reasons, for example in order to send you confirmation of your bookings and your payments, to inform you about your travel itinerary, to notify you when online check in is available or to advise you of disruption and changes to your flight or other arrangements.

Please be aware that these communications are not made for marketing purposes and as such, you will continue to receive them even if you opt-out from receiving marketing communications.

We will also use your personal data if we contact you after you have sent us a request, filled in a web-form through our website or contacted us on social media. 

Your opinion is very important to us, so we may send you an email to seek your feedback.

We will use the communications you exchange with us and the feedback you may provide in order to manage our relationship with you as our customer and to improve our services and experiences for customers generally. 

  * **To personalise and improve your customer experience**

We may use your personal data in order to tailor our services to your needs and preferences and to provide you with a personalised customer experience. For example, if you inform us about your preferred departure airports we will be able to send you offers for flights and holidays relevant to your location and preference.

We may also collect information on how you use our website, which pages of our website you visit most, which flights you search for and what products you buy, in order to understand what you like. We may use this information to tailor the content and offers that you see on our website and, to send you relevant messages that we think you might like.  

If you are in the process of making a booking and you leave our website before your booking has been completed, we may contact you by telephone or email in order to assist you in completing your booking.   

  * **To inform you about our news and offers that you may like**

We may send you marketing communications, for example when you make a booking with us and you do not opt out of receiving such communications. You can also request us to send you marketing communications through a request on our website or by emailing us at marketing@olympicholidays.com. If you are happy to receive marketing communications, we will provide you with news from us such as new destinations that you may be interested in or offers or promotions that you may like. Such offers may include information about flights, accommodation and other associated travel products that are available on our website and are offered to you while making a booking with us.  
In addition, if you are happy to receive marketing communications, we may send you communications promoting our partners’ products and services that may be related to your holiday or travel arrangements. These products may include: airport parking, airport lounges, airport hotels specific flight seat and additional baggage reservations, and other products. Please note that this is not an exhaustive list and is subject to change.   
Please note that we do not share your contact details and other personal data with other companies for marketing purposes, unless we have obtained your consent to do so, although if you purchase a product from one of our partners you may provide personal data to them in the process, which they may use in accordance with their own privacy and personal data processing policies.   
If you do not want to receive marketing communications from us, you can simply tell us so by clicking the relevant box before confirming your booking online or informing our consultant if booking by telephone. You can also choose to opt out from receiving marketing communications at any time, by clicking on the relevant unsubscribe link at the bottom of any marketing related email you may receive from us.    
If you prefer, you can also call our Customer Service team and express your preference to not receive marketing communications on 0208 4926799 or send an email to customer.services@olympicholidays.com with the header “Unsubscribe”.

  * **To improve our services, fulfil our administrative purposes and protect our business interests  **

The business purposes for which we will use your information include accounting, billing and audit, credit or other payment card verification, fraud screening, safety, security and legal purposes, statistical and marketing analysis, systems testing, maintenance and development. 

  * **To comply with our legal obligations,** for example, our obligation to provide your information to border control agencies, or if you are employed to provide returns and information to HM Revenue and Customs or similar bodies in other countries.

  4. **Your rights in relation to your personal data**

  * You have a right to request access to the personal data that we hold about you. This could include booking information relating to holidays or other arrangements you have booked or taken with us.
  * You have the right to request rectification of inaccurate data we hold about you
  * You have the right to request a copy of all personal data we hold about you and, unless you otherwise specify we will supply this copy in a commonly used electronic form.
  * You have the right to data portability, which means you have the right to receive or, where possible, to have transferred to another data controller personal data which we hold about you, in a commonly used machine-readable format
  * The right to erasure ("Right to be forgotten"): where the purpose for which personal data was collected has been completed and subject to any requirement of law or for the purpose of making or defending legal proceedings, you may ask that we erase all such personal data
  * You have the right, in the event that you consider that you have any issue with the way in which we have collected, stored, or processed the data we hold about you to complain to the Information Commissioner. In that event you should contact the Information Commissioner's Office, Telephone 0303 123 1113 (if calling from within the UK) or +44 1625 545 700 (if calling from outside the UK) or you can email via their website: [www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/).

If you would like to request a copy of your personal data or make any other request in relation to it, please contact us at: privacypolicy@olympicholidays.com

  5. **Security of your personal data**

We are committed to taking appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect your personal data against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage to personal data. When you provide your personal data through our website, this information is transmitted across the internet securely using high-grade encryption. If we obtain it by other means, e.g. when you telephone us, it will be entered onto and held on systems that are protected by technical and other means against loss or damage.

Furthermore, Olympic Holidays is a PCI DSS compliant organisation. This means that we adhere to high security standards in order to protect your payment card details when you are sending us this information. 

As described in this Privacy Policy, we may in some instances disclose your personal data to third parties. Where we disclose your personal data to a third party, we require that third party to have appropriate measures in place to protect your personal data; however in some instances we may be compelled by law to disclose your personal data to a third party, such as HM Revenue and Customs, and have limited control over how it is protected by that organisation.

The information that you provide to us will be held in our systems, which are located on our premises or those of appointed third parties. We may also allow access to your information by other third parties who act for us for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy or for other purposes approved by you. Your personal data may be accessed by and processed outside the European Economic Area (the European Economic Area being the European Union and Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway, also referred to as the “EEA”) - including by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers or agents (this includes staff engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your booking, ground handlers, and the provision of support services). Where your personal data are transferred outside of the EEA, we require that appropriate safeguards are in place. 

We will retain your personal data for as long as we need it in order to fulfil our purposes set out in this Privacy Policy or in order to comply with the law. 

  6. **Cookies or other tracking technologies**

In order to improve our services, to provide you with more relevant content and to analyse how visitors use our website we may use technologies, such as cookies, pixels or tracking software. Please be aware that in most cases we will not be able to identify you from the information we collect using these technologies.

For example, we use software to monitor customer traffic patterns and website usage to help us develop the design and layout of the website in order to enhance the experience of the visitors to our website. This software does not enable us to collect any personal data. In addition, in order to understand how our customers interact with the emails and the content that we send, we use pixels that allow us to know if the emails we send are opened or if the content of our emails is displayed in text or html form.

We also use cookies in our website or in our emails. Cookies are small pieces of information stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. They assist you to navigate on our website and allow us to provide features such as remembering aspects of your last flight search to make subsequent searches faster. You can use your browser settings to block and delete cookies if you wish; while cookies are not necessary for viewing and navigating on our website, certain features will work better or faster if cookies are enabled. The only cookies we use are "session" cookies, which mean that they are installed on your device only for the duration of your visit to our website. They are then automatically disabled. No identifiable information about you is obtained or stored by our cookies.

For more information on how we use cookies and how you can remove them, read our [Cookie Policy.](https://www.olympicholidays.com/cookies/ "Cookies")

  7. **Sharing your personal data**

We share some of your personal data with, or obtain your personal data from, the following third parties or categories of third parties for the purposes set out in the table below:

**Identity/Category**

| 

**Purpose**  
  
---|---  
  
Interaction Worldwide Ltd a company incorporated in England and Wales under number 02934755 with its registered office at 25 Moorgate, London EC2R 6AY

| 

To carry out the making and administration of your booking and to carry out sales and marketing activity on our behalf. Also to employ staff for these purposes and to assist you at your destination in Greece and Cyprus during your holiday.  
  
Olympic Holidays Group Ltd a company incorporated in Cyprus and having its registered office at 7, Makedonias, PO Box 54270, CY4001, Limassol, CYPRUS

| 

To process your data to arrange the provision of your accommodation, transfers and other ground arrangements during your holiday, and subsequently to deal with payments to suppliers in respect of your holiday or accommodation arrangements. If you are employed as resort staff Olympic Holidays Group Ltd will also deal with the calculation of payment of your salary and other payments.  
  
Powerclass Sytems Ltd a company incorporated in Cyprus and having its registered office at  4 Regas Fereos Street, Omega Court, 1st floor, 3095 Limassol, Cyprus

| 

To provide and ensure the maintenance of our reservations and other IT systems including data storage systems.  
  
Atcore Technology Group Ltd a company incorporated in England and Wales under number 9022905 and with its registered office at 353 Buckingham Avenue, Slough SL1 4PF

| 

The hosting of our reservations system hardware and provision and maintenance of our reservations, administration and finance software, including data storage and processing.  
  
Other business partners and suppliers

| 

We work with a number of businesses which provide various services in the fields of documentation, ancillary products or website and other design or maintenance services. During the course of the provision of those services these businesses may acquire some or all of the personal data you have given us.  
  
Retail Travel Agents

| 

If you choose to make your booking via a retail or online travel agent, they will initially obtain personal data from you and share some of it with us for the purpose of providing the services booked and administering your holiday and travel arrangements.  
  
Airlines

| 

The provision of flight seats and ancillary services by the airline you have selected as part of your flight inclusive travel arrangements. Some airlines/destinations require the provision of Advanced Passenger Information (API) that is more detailed information about you for security purposes.  
  
Hotels and other accommodation owners/managers

| 

The provision of accommodation and any ancillary services during your holidays  
  
Providers of coach, taxi and ferry services at your destination

| 

To secure the provision of transfers between your arrival airport and accommodation as booked by you.  
  
PricewaterhouseCoopers of 43 Demostheni Severi Avenue, CY-1080 Nicosia, Cyprus

| 

PricewaterhouseCoopers provide us with accountancy and auditing services and in the course of providing those services may come into possession of and process your personal data.  
  
The UK Civil Aviation Authority ("CAA")

| 

We are licensed by the CAA and in the course of the licensing process or their regulation of licensed companies we may share personal data with them.  
  
The Association of British Travel Agents Ltd ("ABTA")

| 

We are members of ABTA who amongst other things provide additional financial protection for our clients and in the process of administering that membership or providing dispute resolution services or a complaints procedure, we may share personal data with ABTA.  
  
  8. **Updates to our Privacy Policy**

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will publish on our website any new version of this Policy.

  9. **Contact information**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be emailed to [privacypolicy@olympicholidays.com](mailto:privacypolicy@olympicholidays.com) or by post to: Operations Department, Olympic Holidays, 1 Torrington Park, London, N12 9TB.
